BRAYDEN BERTRAND

2653 Commercial Drive Vancouver, BC, V5N 4C3 778-995-8545

https://ca.linkedin.com/in/brayden-bertrand-b93962b7

SUMMARY

Highly motivated diligent automation professional with an expertise in:

C# Software Development	Team Management
C++ Software Development	Testing tool Creation
Automation Experience	Training Developers
Jenkins, Selenium	Creating Test plans
Java, Groovy, Python	Internal and External Communication Skills

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

OnGuard Security 2019-Present

Automation/Business technology, Software Developer

2019-PRESENT

- Developing software to replace outmoded industry standard applications with solutions that best solve the issues hindering the service teams.
- Collecting data on various levels of the company to display to the stakeholders to allow them to make more accurate decisions on how to improve the organization's process and efficiency.

Electronic Arts 2015-2019

NHL Automation, Software Developer in Test

2017-2019

- Creating Automation scripts to test the NHL video game.
- Managing the NHL Automation Farm and the NHL automation script execution.
- Writing and maintaining technical documentation on automation and reporting.
- Training new software engineers.
- Communication with remote teams in Romania, with the QA team and the Romanian engineers.
- Communication with the EA NHL QA team and assisting with the creation of test plans.
- Working with the newly created Data team and assisting with the transition of responsibilities from the Automation team.
- Assisting with the creation of a new bug reporting pipeline for the QA team in regards to Automation.
- Creating reports for NHL Leadership to gain insight on the state of the game.
- Communicating with NHL Leadership on the current state of the NHL Automation.

Fifa Quality Assurance, Quality Analyst

2016-2017

- Writing Test plans to identify problem areas within the application.
- Executing test plans and logging the results to allow the Development team to fix any found issues
- Inter-team communication and organization. Communication between game teams was needed for improving the testing process.

NoTime Studios 2015-2017

Team Management, Lead Software Developer

2016-2019

- Creating coding architecture for the product alongside designers in a multi disciplined team.
- Writing and maintaining all project related technical documentation.
- Managing a team of five engineers that then ramped up to eight with three contractors near the end of the project cycle.

Application Development, C# Software Developer

2015-2016

2016-2016

- Application development in C#.
- Actively participating in an Agile development process.
- Code reviews, and other code quality assurance tasks.

Inkpad Studios 2016-2016

Application and tool Development, C# Software Developer

- Application development in C#.
- Actively participating in an Agile development process.
- Code reviews, and other code quality assurance tasks.
- Tool creation to help the overall production of the project and future projects.

Premium Fire Protection 2013-2014

Team Management, Technician manager

2013-2014

- Managing a team of four Technicians, assuring the team is synced up on tasks, know what they
 need to do next, and what tasks go to who.
- Continued with all my previous Technician tasks.

Information Technology, Technician

2013-2013

- Setting up and maintaining servers and databases.
- Fixing any and all computer or equipment related issues in the head office.
- Traveling in between the other branches to resolve large scale issues.
- Workstation setup.
- Virus removal and security.
- Password recovery.
- Updating the Premium Fire's website.

EDUCATION

SQL Fundamentals, SoloLearn Certification
C++, SoloLearn Certification
C#, SoloLearn Certification
PHP, SoloLearn Certification
HTML, SoloLearn Certification
Computer Science Course Basics in C++
Game Design Program, Vancouver Film School (GD39)
Advanced Unity Development, Digipen Institute of technology